Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/hellermann (LinkedIn) www.foundamental.com (Company)

Top-Kenntnisse

Breakthrough Thinking Entrepreneurship Startups

Languages

Englisch (Full Professional)

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)

Patric H.

General Partner @ Foundamental. Always available for hungry entrepreneurs in construction and renovation tech.

Metropolregion Berlin/Brandenburg

Zusammenfassung

My goal is to help exceptional founders realize their highest ambitions in construction and renovation tech. I work alongside entrepreneurs from the earliest stages as their business partner, drawing upon my B2B/industrial operating experience at thyssenkrupp (TYEKF) and E.ON (EOAN) and my CleanTech experience.

I am captivated when founders create simplicity and instant value. I am also drawn to business models built on frequency or transparency.

Within the Foundamental family, I work with a broad range of companies in construction, renovation and mining. Some rewire the industry's tech stack; some create low-friction high-reliability purchasing; and others disrupt markets through asset networks. All of them are led by inspirational founders and management teams who combine exceptional operators capabilities with unique domain insights in construction, renovation and mining.

For more details, visit: https://foundamental.com/people/patric-hellermann/

Specialties: Asset networks in off-site/prefab, full-stack full-service models, APIs and protocols, multi-parameter optimization

-based. Opinions are my own.

Berufserfahrung

Foundamental
Founding Partner, GP
Juli 2018 - Present (3 Jahre 10 Monate)

The global investor in construction and renovation technology

Rayon

Investor

Februar 2022 - Present (3 Monate)

Paris, Île-de-France, Frankreich

Stealth Mode

Investor

August 2021 - Present (9 Monate)

Germany

Conversational commerce for home renovations

Tul

Investor

Juli 2021 - Present (10 Monate)

Kolumbien

The leading one-stop shop enabling the construction materials supply chain for SMB hardware stores across Latin America

Graneet

Investor

Juni 2021 - Present (11 Monate)

Paris, Île-de-France, France

The Quickbooks / Khatabook for construction SMBs in Europe

Stealth

Investor

Mai 2021 - Present (1 Jahr)

Somewhere in Europe

Something in construction. I can't talk about it

Kompozite

Investor

März 2021 - Present (1 Jahr 2 Monate)

France

The Stylight for construction materials

011h

Investor

Dezember 2020 - Present (1 Jahr 5 Monate)

Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

Next-generation developer+general contractor for multi-family housing in the European build-to-rent market, built on an integrated tech and supply stack with an asset-light supply network.

Flinkit

Investor

Dezember 2020 - Present (1 Jahr 5 Monate)

Germany

Stealth Startup

Investor

Mai 2020 - Present (2 Jahre)

United Kingdom

The Github for 3D design

Juno

Investor

Mai 2020 - Present (2 Jahre)

San Francisco Bay Area

Asset-light developer+general contractor bringing the North American multifamily homes of the future.

ALICE Technologies Inc.

Investor

Mai 2019 - Present (3 Jahre)

San Francisco Bay Area

HoloBuilder

Investor

Januar 2019 - Juni 2021 (2 Jahre 6 Monate)

San Francisco Bay Area

Exit. Acquired by Faro.

Trelar

Investor

November 2018 - März 2020 (1 Jahr 5 Monate)

Austin, Texas Area

Exit. Acquired by T.Rowe Price and HaulHub

Techstars

Mentor

Januar 2017 - März 2020 (3 Jahre 3 Monate)

Berlin Area, Germany

Global accelerator and ecosystem that helps entrepreneurs build great businesses. Comparable to Y Combinator, 500 Startups.

thyssenkrupp

MD and Investor, thyssenkrupp Garage

Juli 2014 - November 2017 (3 Jahre 5 Monate)

Germany

Multinational technology conglomerate: €42 billion sales, 160'000 employees. Comparable to Siemens, Lockheed-Martin, ABB.

HELLERMANN & COMPANY

Founder and CEO

2015 - 2017 (2 Jahre)

Germany

Inventor-producer of an innovative solution to store luxury mechanical watches for collectors. Handed over CEO role in February 2017.

E.ON

Manager

2010 - 2014 (4 Jahre)

Germany

Strategy group (in-house consulting) of the world's largest investor-owned utility. €120 billion sales, 62'000 employees. Mentored by various former McKinsey and BCG Principals.

goetzpartners

Associate

2008 - 2010 (2 Jahre)

Germany

Leading European Private Equity and M&A consultancy. Led by former McKinsey and Bain Partners. 350+ consultants, 14 offices worldwide.

Ausbildung

Tsinghua University

Master's, Business Administration · (2007)

Purdue University Krannert School of Management Master's, Business Administration · (2007)

London Business School PgD Corporate Finance · (2010)

Universität Duisburg-Essen
Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Energy Management · (2003)